Alexander Andom Solomon

 $Abu\ Dhabi,\ UAE,\ +971545001884,\ alexashie.solomon@gmail.com$

PROFILE	 Motivated IT graduate specialized in Networking and Cybersecurity, adept in network administration, penetration testing, software development and data analytics. Actively pursuing opportunities to apply my professional expertise and make substantial contributions. 	
EXPERIENCE		
Jan 2022 — Jun 2023	Teaching Assistant (part time), Zayed University	Abu Dhabi
	 Enhanced education through active lesson and resource development Ignited student success with personalized support and focused attention. 	
Jan 2021 — May 2021	Teaching Assistant (part time), Zayed University	Abu Dhabi
	 Ensured quality by meticulously testing lab materials before distribution to students. Empowered students in mastering technical aspects through dedicated assistance. 	
Jan 2020 — Dec 2022	Pear Assistant Leader (PAL) (part time), Zayed University	Abu Dhabi
	 Providing tailored guidance to students for success in diverse IT courses. Sparked academic achievement by providing individualized assistance 	
EDUCATION		
Nov 2022 — Present	Software Development, 42 Abu Dhabi, UAE	Abu Dhabi
	 conducted 50+ peer evaluations collaborated on diverse projects, notably minishell, cub3d and ft_irc. 	
Jan 2019 — Dec 2022	BSc in IT, Networking and Cyber security, Zayed University,	Abu Dhabi
	Graduated with honors of CGPA 3.91.Honored with golden visa award for academic excellence.	
PROJECTS		
Nov 2023 — Dec 2023	ft_irc	
	 Description: Developed a lightweight Internet Relay Chat (IRC) server called ft_irc, using C++. Designing and implementing IRC protocol functionalities for user management and real-time messaging. Role: Lead Developer Technologies: C++, Networking protocols, Socket programming 	
Jun 2023 — Aug 2023	Cub3d	
	 Description: Developed a 3D game using Ray-Casting techniques for the Cub3D project at 42 abu dhabi. Implemented graphics rendering, player movement, and map parsing as Lead Developer Role: Lead Developer Technologies: C, Ray-Casting Techniques, MinilibX Library 	
May 2023 — Jul 2023	minishell	
	 Description: Created a Unix shell, minishell, akin to the Bash shell. Tasks involved designing and implementing shell functionalities, refining command parsing, and optimizing execution processes. Role: lead programmer Technologies: C, Shell scripting techniques, System calls 	
Aug 2022 — Dec 2022	ZUOnlineRegistrationSystem	
	 Description: an optimized web-based course enrollment system. Implemented user-friendly features for streamlined course browsing, scheduling, registration, and add/drop services using Machine learning technique. Role: Front end Developer Technologies: PHP, html, css, Javascript, MySQL and Machine learning (Genetic Algorithm) 	

SKILLS

Programing languages (C, C++,

python and Java))

Database management (oracle

and mysql)

Microsoft Office

Data analysis using r

Network Administration (CCNA routing and switching)

Cyber security penetration

testing (kali)

CERTIFICATIONS

2023 Certification of completion in Data Structures and Algorithms:

Deep Dive Using Java,

2020 CCNAv7: Introduction to Networks Cisco Certification

2020 CCNAv7: Switching, Routing and Wireless Essentials Cisco

Certification

2020 Global Connect & Global Circles Certification of Completion:

Soliya program

HONORS AND AWARDS

Jan 2019 — May 2022 dean's list Semester (Six times)

Zayed University

• Completes a minimum of 15 gradable credit hours in a semester while maintaining a GPA of 3.70 and above.

Dec 2022 Highest Distinction

Zayed University

• A student graduated with CGPA of 3.9 and above.

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Feb 2019 — Dec 2022 Valley ball Team, Zayed University

Abu Dhabi

• Represented Zayed University in Volleyball competitions 3 seasons.

Dec 2019 — Aug 2022 African Caribbean Club

Abu Dhabi

• Representing Eritrea in the club, presenting Eritrean cultural traditions in different events.